A Finding Aid to the Chester Beach Papers, 1846-1999, bulk circa 1900-1999, in the Archives of American Art AAA.beacches
Archives of American Art
- Project Files, 1846-1999; Series 2; 1.6 Linear feet Boxes 1-2, 11, OV 12-13
  - Seliger - Portraits of two daughters (terra cotta, 1931?), undated; 1932 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Service to the Nation in War and Peace (A. T. and T.; bronze and marble), undated; 1924-1926; oversized material housed in OV 13 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Skidmore - Ann Skidmore, undated; 1965 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Sleeping, Two Days Old (marble, 1912), undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Snowflake Dance (marble, 1913), undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Spirit of the Greek Games (Barnard College; bronze, undated; 1924-1999 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Spring (marble, 1912), undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Stoiber Tombstone (1920?), undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - The Stoker, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Stuyvesant - Augustus Van Horne Stuyvesant Memorial (St. Mark's Church In-the-Bowery; marble, 1918), 1953-1984; undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Sun and Earth; Fountain of the Waters (Cleveland Museum of Art; marble), 1926-1996; See also: Box 1, F 28-35 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Sundial, Touchstone Garden, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Surf (bronze; later version carved in marble), undated; 1926-1947 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Swimmin' (marble, 1907), undated; 1942-1947 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Sylvan (marble, 1928), 1924-1968; undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Tefft - Ethel Tefft, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Thorne - Jonathan Thorne (bronze, 1910), undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - To the City of Immigrants (1908), undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Toto (ivory, 1922), undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Townsend Memorial (bronze), undated; 1934-1936 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Underwood - Senator Oscar W. Underwood (U. S. Capitol; marble, 1933) (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, Notes, Drawings, Printed Material, undated; 1932-1942 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Unfolding of Life (marble), 1914 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Union Square Park Memorial Competition (commission not awarded [4th place]), undated; 1926 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Unveiling of Dawn (marble, 1912), undated; 1917-1948 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Vitale - Gioia Vitale, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Vortex of Life (marble), 1993; undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - War and Peace Medal (bronze), 1968; undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - War Medals - American Defense Service Medal; Good Conduct Medal, 1941-1942; undated (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Washington - George Washington Monument at Fort Necessity (not funded), 1931-1932 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Waterfall (marble, 1908), 1915 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Wave Head, undated (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Wave Horses, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Weber - Carl Maria von Weber (bronze, 1909), undated (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Wells - Florence Wells (intaglio in mother of pearl; locket size in bronze), 1933-1992; undated (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Whitman - Walt Whitman (Hall of Fame for Great Americans, NY; bronze, 1931), 1931-1938; undated (Box 2, Folder 64)
    See: Box 1, F66
  - Whitney - Eli Whitney (Hall of Fame for Great Americans, NY; bronze, 1924), 1846-1926; undated (Box 2, Folder 65)
    See: Box 1, F 67
  - Wilkes - Lemmuel Wilkes (bronze, 1909), 1922; undated (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Woods Figure (bronze, 1912), undated (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Young Nymph I, 1910; undated (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Young Pan/Child Pan, undated (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Zodiac (Cleveland Museum of Art; marble), undated; 1926-1928; (See also: Box 1, F 28-35) (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Oversized items removed from Project Files, 1924-1997; Box 2, F 34, Box 2, F 57 (Box 11)
  - Oversized items from Project Files, 1909-1942; Box 2, F 50 (Box OV 12)
  - Oversized items from Project Files, 1924-1938; Box 2, F 52 (Box OV 13)
- Business Records, circa 1900-1958; Series 3; 0.4 Linear feet Box 2
  Business records include Chester Beach's general business correspondence and correspondence concerning consignments. An address book - alphabetized by services and products - records names, addresses, and sometimes prices. Included among the entries are: "enlarging and reducing; enlarging bust to heroic size," a "marble cutter (first class)" in Florence, a stair builder, photographers, pedestals, and ventilators. The volume recording building expenses and income contains lists of equipment, the effects of William Couper and their disposition, rents collected, coal purchased, etc. The check register documents payments to foundries, purchases of marble, models, dies, and other supplies and services. Beach's record book, 1907-1947, lists sales (noting title, price, and buyer) and bronzes cast. The same volume also contains names and addresses of clients, dealers, services, tools and supplies; inside its back cover are instructions for cleaning marble and plaster, and for bronzing plaster.
  Additional business records are scattered among most of the project files (Series 3), and a small number of business letters are preserved in scrapbook volumes 1 and 2 (Series 8).
  - Address Book, 1914; (1 volume) (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Building Expenses and Income, 207 East 17th Street, 1913-1914; (1 volume) (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Check Register, 1922-1924; (1 volume) (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Consignments (Box 2)
    - The Gorham Company, undated; 1927-1947 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Grand Central Galleries, 1928-1958 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - William Macbeth, 1908-1916 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Tiffany and Co., 1926-1936 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Miscellaneous (A-Z), 1908-1955 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Correspondence, General Business, undated; circa 1900-1956; 3 Folders (Box 2, Folder 79-81)
  - Invoices, 1909-1934 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Lists of Glass Plate Negatives in Boxes 1, B-L, and O, undated; (1 volume and loose sheets) (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Lists of Photographs, undated (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Record Book, circa 1909-1947; undated; (1 volume) (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Sculpture Inventories and Lists, Orders, Prizes, etc., 1915-1916; (1 volume) (Box 2, Folder 86)
- Writings, 1913-1935; Series 4; 2 Folders Box 3
  Chester Beach's writings consist of "The Art Course in College" and general statements on art. The writings about him are "History and Allegory with a Silver Lining: Silver Coins and Medals by Chester Beach, N.A. 1881-1956" by Eleanor Beach Fitchen, and biographical sketches by Lee Lawrie and an unidentified author.
  An unfinished poem by FitzRoy Carrington to Chester Beach and Eleanor Hollis Murdock is preserved in scrapbook volume 1 (Series 8).
  - By Chester Beach, 1913-1935; undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - About Chester Beach, circa 1966-1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1875; 1933-1996; Series 5; 0.5 Linear feet Box 3
  With the exception of a nineteenth century letter addressed to a relative of Mrs. Beach, most letters are addressed to Chester Beach's widow and their daughter, Eleanor Beach Fitchen. Many mention Chester Beach. Estate correspondence and related documents, created mainly by the sculptor's daughter, Eleanor Beach Fitchen, concern efforts to exhibit or sell Beach's remaining work and maintain his reputation.
  Project files (Series 2) contain the majority of Beach's professional correspondence. General business correspondence is filed among his business records (Series 3), and additional correspondence is found in volumes 1 and 2 of the scrapbooks (Series 8). A few Christmas cards (Series 5) contain notes from friends.
  The series is arranged as 2 subseries:
  Subseries 1: Family Correspondence, 1875-1996
  Subseries 2: Estate Correspondence and Related Documents, 1956-1999
  - Family Correspondence, 1875-1996; 5.1
    The 1875 letter to George Murdock from Mame relays news of family and friends. Among the small number of letters to Mrs. Beach is one from Walker Hancock reminiscing about their days at the American Academy in Rome.
    Letters to Eleanor Beach Fitchen are mostly from friends, and one from each of her sisters; several mention her father.
    - Murdock Family Letter, 1875 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Letters to Mrs. Chester Beach (Eleanor Hollis Murdock Beach), 1944-1963 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Letters to Eleanor Beach Fitchen ("Toto"), undated; 1933-1996 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Estate Correspondence and Related Documents, 1956-1999; 5.2
    Estate correspondence and related documents were created mainly by Chester Beach's daughter, Eleanor Beach Fitchen; also found are a very small number of letters addressed to or from her mother and sisters. Mrs. Fitchen acted as the estate's sales agent, ran the Chester Beach Memorial Studio, sought exhibition opportunities, and worked to maintain her father's reputation.
    Letters from Brenda Kuhn to Eleanor Beach Fitchen concern estate management and relate some of what she learned from handling the estate of her father, Walt Kuhn. The letters include ideas and advice about exhibitions, the Memorial Studio, and the Beach Centennial.
    A letter from sculptor Walker Hancock, filed with "Letters, Miscellaneous," contains advice about posthumous castings. "Studio Building, 207 East 17th Street" contains a letter from the great-granddaughter of sculptor William Couper, who sold the property to Beach around 1913; Mrs. Fitchen's reply relates the building's history, as she recalls being told by her parents.
    - Article Proposals Declined, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Centennial of Beach's Birth, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Consignments, 1956-1965 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      The Gorham Company
      James Graham and Sons
      Grand Central Art Galleries
      Purnell Art Gallery
    - Curators/Scholars/Writers, 1977-1994 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Exhibition Proposals and Gifts Declined, 1963-1969 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Exhibitions (Box 3)
      - "The Armory Show 50th Anniversary Exhibition," Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute and Henry Street Settlement, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - "The Figure in American Sculpture," Los Angeles County Museum of Art, 1991-1995 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - "Fresh Air Sculpture," National Sculpture Society at America's Tower, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - "Outdoor Sculpture Exhibition," C. W. Nelson Nursery, Sandisfield, MA, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - "Sculptors of United States Coins," Chase Manhattan Money Museum, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Gifts of Sculpture, 1964-1997 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Letters from Brenda Kuhn, 1962-1971 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Letters, Miscellaneous, 1968-1998 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Photograph Requests and Reproduction Permissions, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Requests for Corrections, 1960-1996 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Research (Box 3)
      - Commissions (1908-1951), Prizes, Sales, circa 1960s (Box 3, Folder 21)
        photocopy
      - Lists of Sculpture, Available Work, Photographs, 1956-1968 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - Notes, circa 1960s-1990s (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - Sales (1919-1961), circa 1961 (Box 3, Folder 24)
        card index
    - Sales (Box 3)
      - Chester Beach Sculpture, 1965-1987; undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - Eleanor Beach Paintings, 1965-1970 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - Not Completed, 1964-1966; undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - Pending (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Studio Building, 207 East 17th Street, 1959-1986 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Christmas Cards, 1909-1961; Series 6; 0.7 Linear feet Boxes 3-4
  This series consists of cards sent and received by Chester Beach. The earliest cards sent by Chester Beach featured his dog, whose image was soon replaced by those of the Beach children. A complete set of cards produced and sent by Beach are included in the album; those sent after his death reproduce the work of Mrs. Beach.
  Christmas cards received by the Beach family are mostly artist-designed cards, many containing original artwork; in some instances, the sender is not the artist. Cards are from Ernest Blumenschein, Edward W. Greacen, Hazel Brill Jackson, Paul Jennewein, Bonnie Leibig, F. Luis Mora, Robert Nisbet, Ezra Winter, and other artists. One of Walker Hancock's cards features a photograph of his studio. A card from Anna Hyatt Huntington's card reproduces a painting of Beach's Sylvan at Brookgreen Gardens. Beach patron Mary Jester Allen's includes a note mentioning the Frontier Art Colony she was establishing near Cody, Wyoming.
  Cards are arranged alphabetically by name of sender. A few of Beach's original designs for Christmas cards are filed with artwork (Series 7).
  - Abbott family - Barnes family, undated; 1939 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Beach, Chester and family, undated; 1911-1957; (loose cards (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Beach, Chester and family, 1909-1961; (1 volume, disbound) (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Beach, Marion D. - Brinckerhoff, A. F., 1925-1950; undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Carrington, FitzRoy - Cross, Hollis and Harriett, 1922-1940; undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Dankin, Susan D. H. and H. D. - Demming, Edwin W. and family, 1919-1942; undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - De Silver, Ann and family - Duell, Prentice, 1920-1940; undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Eberle, Betty - Fairbanks, David and Barbara, 1921-1940; undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Gates family - Greacen, Mr. and Mrs. Edmund W., 1915-1931; undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Hancock, Walker - Huntington, Anna Hyatt and Archer, undated; 1935-1944 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Ivins, William and Florence - Jones, Carlyle and Rosalie, undated; 1926-1961 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Ladd, Dr. and Mrs. William Sargent - Lloyd, Dr. and Mrs. Henry D., undated; 1930-1961 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - MacDonald, Pierce - Mora, F. Luis and Rosemary, undated; 1920-1940 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Nisbet, Robert and Marguerite - Nordli family, undated; 1927-1934 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Paquin, Warner and Ella - Rubins, David Kresz, undated; 1917-1930 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Sensargaard, Edwin A. - Sutton, Charles R., undated; 1932 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Taft, Mabel B. - Vitale, Ferruchio and family, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Waid, D. E. - Winter, Mr. and Mrs. Ezra, undated; 1919-1939 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Unidentified (Clive - Milton and Rosamund), 1945-1948; undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Unsigned, 1922-1927, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Artwork, circa 1900-1955; Series 7; 0.3 Linear feet Boxes 4, 11
  Artwork by Chester Beach includes drawings, sketches, and designs for a few of his Christmas cards. The sketchbook contains drawings of sculpture. Work by other artists consists of prints; several are signed, but the only completely legible signature is Ezra Winter
  Project files (Series 3) contain numerous drawings and sketches by Chester Beach, though few are finished artwork. An exception is The Legend of Archmere, with many finished, colored drawings. Among the Christmas cards (series 6) are numerous artist-designed cards, many with original artwork, received by the Beach family. Additional artwork by Chester Beach includes book plates and a place card etched for Mr. and Mrs. George Davison, found in volume 1 of the scrapbooks (Series 8).
  - By Chester Beach - Drawings and Sketches (Box 4)
    - Early Work (San Francisco and Paris), circa 1900-1907; undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Christmas Card Designs, 1911-1955; undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Animals, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Figures, Female, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Figures, Male, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Figures, Couples and Groups, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Heads, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Landscapes, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Medallions and Coins, undated; circa 1926 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous Subjects, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - "Sketches of Cornelia Mil[illegible] in Dutch Costume 1907," (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Sketchbook, undated; (1 vol.) (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - By Other Artists (Box 4)
    - Prints, undated; 1921 (Box 4, Folder 21)
      Oversized material housed in Box 10
    - Artwork by Other Artists - Print by Ezra Winter, undated (Box 11)
- Scrapbooks, 1903-1972; Series 8; 0.3 Linear feet Box 10
  The scrapbooks are largely comprised of newspaper clippings and other printed material.
  Volume 1 contains letters, among them notification of acceptance from the Ecole des Beaux Arts, work accepted for Salon d'Automne; American Academy in Rome announcement of Beach's eligibility to compete in the Prix de Rome preliminary competition, and a letter from Daniel Chester French regretting Beach's descision to withdraw from consideration; membership in The Architectural League of New York and National Sculpture Society; appointment to the Hudson-Fulton Celebration Committee and U.S. Treasury Department Committee for 4th Liberty Loan; and from Jessica B. Piexotto, concerning a medal commemorating Children's Year. There are samples of book plates and a place card etched for Mr. and Mrs. George Davison, and an unfinished poem by FitzRoy Carrington to Chester Beach and Eleanor Hollis Murdock. Photographs include a view of the Mark Hopkins Art Institute's night school class attended by Beach, circa 1900-1902, and a portrait of Chester Beach painted by G. Laurance Nelson. Also found are exhibitors' cards, certificates announcing Beach's election as an Associate member of the National Academy of Design; and the award of a silver medal at the Panama-Pacific International Exposition.
  Volume 2 includes letters from the National Academy of Design about Beach's election as an Academician and the award of a gold medal; and from Frederick MacMonnies commending, Spirit of the Greek Games, Beach's sculpture at Barnard College. Also found are certificates from The Architectural League of New York announcing the award of its Medal of Honor, one naming Beach an Academician of the National Academy of Design, and a photograph of Beach working in his studio.
  Volume 3, with the exception of one letter from Hazel Brill Jackson addressed to Beata Beach Porter, consists only of printed material, mostly newspaper clippings. It begins with obituaries of Chester Beach, and the first page contains the handwritten note "See: Obituary letters" (not part of the 2009 gift of Chester Beach papers described in this finding aid). Other printed items are a catalog of the 1966 Beach memorial exhibition with a related press release, and a brochure about the Chester Beach Memorial Studio in Brewster, New York.
  - Volume 1, 1903-1919; (1 volume) (Box 10)
  - Volume 2, 1919-1935; (1 volume) (Box 10)
  - Volume 3, 1956-1972 (Box 10)
    disbound
- Printed Material, 1910-1997; Series 9; 0.4 Linear feet Box 4
  Most of the printed material is about or mentions Chester Beach, and quite a few items contain reproductions of his work. Panama-Pacific International Exposition guide books are The Jewel City by Ben Macomber, and The Sculpture and Murals of the Panama-Pacific International Exposition, Official Handbook containing commentary on the Beach sculptures commissioned for the exposition. Two brochures are about the Chester Beach Memorial Studio in Brewster, NY, and one from The Society of Medalists reproduces Beach's work. Exhibition catalogs are for solo and group exhibitions. Miscellaneous items are calling cards of Mr. and Mrs. Chester Beach; and "The New Society Dinner of 1923" seating card. Also found is a printing block for a half-tone reproduction of an unidentified Beach sculpture, probably used for an article or catalog.
  General art-related printed items consist of brochures and an exhibition catalog. The brochures are for the "Armory Show 50th Anniversary Exhibition" and The Hall of Fame for Great Americans. Although neither brochure mentions Beach, he participated in the original Armory Show and his work appeared in its anniversary exhibition; and The Hall of Fame for Great Americans commissioned Beach to create six busts. Also found is a catalog, Exhibition of a Loan Collection of the work of Maxfield Parrish, through the kindness of Mr. and Mrs. Austin M. Purves, date unknown, held at the Plastic Club in Philadelphia (Beach became acquainted with the Purveses in 1909 when Mr. Purves commissioned a marble portrait head of his wife).
  Additional printed material is found in many project files (Series 2). All of the scrapbooks (Series 8) contain clippings, and volumes 1 and 2 include a variety of printed items such as exhibition catalogs, brochures, and a newsletter for Académie Julian students.
  - About/Mentioning Beach (Box 4)
    - Articles, undated; 1918-1996 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Books (Box 4)
      - A n Historical Sketch of Fort Hill, Lloyd's Neck, Long Island (with photographs of site for Beach's garden sculpture Glint of the Sea), undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - Everyday Poems by George Elliston (includes "To a Replica of Chester Beach's Night"), 1921 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - Panama-Pacific International Exposition Guide Books, 1915; (2 volumes) (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Brochures, circa 1957-1960s; circa 1947 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1912-1997 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Miscellaneous Items, 1923; undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1945-1966 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Printing Block for Half-tone Reproduction, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Reproductions, 1910 and later (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Art-Related (Box 4)
    - Brochures, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Exhibition Catalog, undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
      N68-11: 192
- Photographs, circa 1885-circa 1960s; Series 10; 3.1 Linear feet Boxes 4-9, 11, 14
  Photographs of artwork by Beach are mainly of sculpture. A large number of duplicate prints were weeded, though multiple copies may still remain. No duplicate glass plate negatives were removed, and their original box letters are noted in the finding aid since there are references to them in many project files. Among the images of early work are drawings from his student days. Both photograph albums are devoted to the sculpture of Chester Beach. It is evident that the many blank pages in Volume 1 once contained photographs. Photographs of artwork by other artists consist of portraits of Chester Beach, by G. Laurance Nelson and one painted posthumously by his daughter, Natalie Beach McLaury.
  Photographs of Chester Beach include an early childhood portrait, circa 1885, and several images of Beach as a young artist by Gertrude Kasebier, circa 1910. There are photographs of Beach in his studio, including him working on portraits of Helen Leeming and Henry L. Doherty. Pictures of Beach with others include a drawing class at the Mark Hopkins Art Institute, with family and friends, and at a "Dinner tendered to Edmund W. Greacen by Samuel T. Shaw, Salmagundi Club, March 2, 1922." Also found are a few photographs of sitters. Places recorded are Beach's boyhood home in San Francisco, the interiors of his New York City and Brewster, NY studios, and Brookgreen Gardens. Miscellaneous subjects are nude models.
  Some photographs of sitters contained in this series are interfiled with their corresponding glass plate negatives; however, most images of sitters are found among the project files (Series 2). Project files also contain a wide variety of other photographs, including: finished work, work in progress, maquettes, plasters, sites, installation, and dedication ceremonies. Scrapbook volumes 1 and 2 (Series 8) contain a few photographs, as do the Christmas cards (Series 6).
  Glass plate negatives are housed separately and closed to researchers.
  - Photograph Albums - Sculpture by Chester Beach (Box 4)
    - Volume 1, undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Volume 2, circa 1940 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Artwork by Chester Beach (Box 4)
    - Early Work, circa 1903-1914 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Coins, undated; 1923-1935 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Sculpture, Panama-Pacific International Exposition, circa 1915 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Sculpture, Identified, undated; (5 folders; oversized material housed in Box 11) (Box 4, Folder 39-43)